playhearthstone.com 2019-12-29

# Blizzard Entertainment Online Privacy Policy - Blizzard Legal

California Residents: Click [HERE](https://www.blizzard.com/en-us/legal/e37112bf-8b02-4df5-b661-f57849b0b1dd/additional-information-california-collection-notice) for the California Collection Notice

Blizzard Entertainment and its subsidiaries (collectively "Blizzard") respects the privacy of its players and online visitors; and recognizes the importance of providing a secure environment for them. We have adopted a company-wide online Privacy Policy (“Privacy Policy”) that explains how we collect, store, and use the information you provide us. This Privacy Policy details how Blizzard safeguards the privacy of its online visitors and does not apply to information that may be collected by Blizzard offline, including but not limited to employment related interactions. When you click a link to other sites from a Blizzard website, this Privacy Policy does not apply to, and cannot control the activities on, those other sites. We highly recommend that you read the privacy policy of any third party website you may be directed to before providing any personally identifiable information.

The personal information you provide may be transferred to, stored, and processed within the United States or other countries where Blizzard maintains facilities or business operations.

By using this website and/or any of Blizzard’s online products or services, you acknowledge the terms of this Privacy Policy. If you object to anything described in this Privacy Policy, please do not use our websites or play our games. This Privacy Policy may change from time to time, so please check back periodically to ensure that you are aware of any changes. If we make a material change to this Privacy Policy, we will notify you by posting the change on our websites or in this Privacy Policy and, if necessary, give you additional choices regarding such change before the change becoming effective. Your continued use of the Blizzard websites will signify your acceptance of these changes.

This Privacy Policy and the certification seals on our websites confirm that Blizzard is a valid licensee, and participating member, in good standing of the [Entertainment Software Rating Board’s Privacy Certified Program](https://www.esrb.org/privacy/) (“ESRB Privacy Certified”). ESRB Privacy Certified is designed to ensure that our information collection, use and disclosure practices are responsible and appropriate. To protect your privacy, we have voluntarily undertaken this privacy initiative, and all of our websites where this Privacy Policy is posted have been reviewed and certified by ESRB Privacy Certified to meet established online information collection, use and disclosure practices.

## 1\. What personal information is collected and how do we use it?

**Information collected from you.** If an online visitor submits information to Blizzard, it will usually be through either: (1) the purchase of goods or services though our online platforms, (2) product or account registration, or registration for online game participation, (3) player match-up services, (4) message boards or forums, (5) eCards or recruit-a-friend e-mails, (6) warranty registrations, (7) contest registrations, (8) the playing of a game or use of a service, (9) surveys, (10) customer service or technical support, (11) Share Wish List feature, and/or (12) newsletters. Personal information collected may include your name, home address, phone number, and/or e-mail address. We do not require this information to gain access to our websites, however, you will not be able to utilize certain products, services, or features that require registration or receive materials such as newsletters unless such information is provided.

Visitors purchasing products or services may have to provide additional information such as a valid credit card number, expiration date, and shipping and billing addresses.

For some activities, we may ask you to create a username and password and/or to provide other personal and non-personal information including but not limited to your age, date of birth, gender, and/or game and platform preferences; and, we may combine such information with other personal and/or non-personal information.

From time to time, we may also post customer testimonials that contain personally identifiable information on Blizzard’s websites. However, we will obtain the customer’s consent to post these testimonials prior to publication in accordance with the applicable Blizzard agreement.

Additionally, communications made using a product or service should not be considered private. Blizzard may monitor and/or record your communications (including without limitation chat text) when you are using a product or service for toxicity analysis, to prevent cheating and fraud, or for enforcement of Blizzard’s End User License Agreement (EULA) and/or terms of use. You hereby provide your irrevocable, express consent to such monitoring and recording. You acknowledge and agree that you have no expectation of privacy concerning the transmission of any user generated content or communications, including without limitation chat text or voice communications. Because voice chat and other communications may be viewed and/or heard by other users, users should avoid revealing any personally identifiable information in those communications.

**Information Collected Automatically.** In addition, your web browser or client software may transmit certain geographic information or information regarding your computer (capabilities, game data processing, etc.) to Blizzard. Blizzard may use this information to generate aggregate statistics about our user community. In addition, Blizzard may use such information for security, system integrity (the prevention of hacking, cheats, etc.), or enforcement purposes. Blizzard may also collect IP information, which it may use to infer your approximate location.

**Information collected from third parties (our vendors, affiliates, and business partners).** Blizzard may enhance or merge the personal information collected at a Blizzard website with data from third parties in order to update your contact information, perform market analysis, or improve our products, services, or systems. If you register an account using your Facebook credentials, the following information may be collected: (1) your first and last name and other information made publicly available by you, (2) your friends list, and (3) the email address associated with your account. Similar data exchanges will occur when you link your Blizzard account with other companies, such as Twitch and console platforms.

**How we use your information.** The personal information you provide Blizzard, and that Blizzard collects automatically, will allow us to provide our games and services, fulfill your product or service order; alert you of new products or services, features, or enhancements; handle/route your customer service or technical support questions or issues; to send eCards or “recruit-a-friend” emails; and/or notify you of upgrade opportunities, contests, promotions, or special events and offers. We also use this information to secure our services and users, to prevent cheating and fraud, to monitor for toxicity, and to enforce our agreements with you.

Last, we may use your personal information for internal marketing or demographic purposes and so we can adapt our products and services to better suit your needs. We do this to better understand and serve our customers.

Personal information submitted by individuals acting solely in a business capacity is not subject to the uses set forth above or to any other practices stated in this Privacy Policy. This includes employees and former employees.

**Additional Information (California Collection Notice).** In the chart below, we identify each category of personal information that we have collected in the last 12 months. For each category of personal information we have collected, we also identify (i) the source(s) from which the information was collected; (ii) the purpose(s) for which it was collected; and (iii) the categories of third parties, if any, with which it has been shared.

Each category of information is collected for the purposes listed below and (1) to provide our games and services, (2) for fraud prevention and legal purposes, (3) to secure our services and users, including to prevent cheating and bad behavior, and (4) for audit purposes.

Data within each of the categories of data above may be shared with third parties for the following purposes:  
• With partners and service providers to operate our systems, deliver goods or services you have requested, or to assist us with marketing;  
• With other players and/or the general public, through your use of certain features of our games and services;  
• With subsidiaries and affiliates for the purposes described in this Privacy Policy to provide you with our games and services;  
• For legal reasons or in the event of a dispute;  
• If necessary, to protect the vital interests of any person; and  
• In connection with the sale of our business or assets

## 2\. What type of communications may you receive?

### Offers

We will occasionally send you information on products, services, special deals, and promotions. Out of respect for your privacy, we present the option not to receive these communications. Please see the “Choice” section below.

### Service-related Announcements

We will send you strictly service-related announcements on rare occasions when it is necessary to do so. You will also receive communication regarding your account security, such as reminders to reset your password and alerts related to changes and suspicious login activity on your account. Generally, you may not opt-out of these communications, which are not promotional in nature.

### Game-related Announcements

We may send you information related to the game(s) you play. For instance, we may congratulate you on your recent success.

### Customer Service

Based upon the personally identifiable information you provide us, we will send you a welcoming email to verify your username and password. We will also communicate with you in response to your inquiries, to provide the services you request, and to manage your account.

### Recruit a Friend/E-cards/Share Wish List

If you choose to use our recruit-a-friend, Share Wish List, or e-card features, we will ask you for your friend’s name and email address. We will automatically send your friend a one-time email inviting him or her to visit the website. Blizzard does not store this information and uses it solely to send this one-time email and to track the success of our referral program.

## 3\. Who is collecting your information?

When you are asked for information while on a Blizzard website or in a Blizzard game or service, you are providing that information to Blizzard Entertainment, Inc. and its subsidiaries unless specifically stated otherwise in that location or in this Privacy Policy.

Occasionally, Blizzard may use third party contractors to collect and process personal information on its behalf (for product and prize fulfillment, etc.). In these instances, Blizzard controls the use of your data via written contracts which conform to this Privacy Policy.

In addition, some services are provided with partner companies. For instance, if you purchase something from Blizzard and ask that it be sent to you via FedEx, your information will be collected by FedEx. If you do not want your information shared, you can choose not to allow the transfer of information by not using that service or by not providing any information. Please be aware that we cannot control all of the activities of third parties to whom we provide data, and while we cannot guarantee that they adhere to the same privacy and security procedures as Blizzard, we will take reasonable steps to assure that these third parties will sufficiently protect personal information.

Our websites may include certain social media features such as the Facebook "Like" button, and widgets such as the Share this button or interactive mini-programs that run on our websites. These features may collect your Internet Protocol (“IP”) address, which page you are visiting on our websites, and may set a cookie to enable the feature to function properly. Social media features and widgets are hosted by a third party or hosted directly on our websites. Your interactions with these features are governed by the privacy policy of the company providing it.

## 4\. With whom may your personal information be shared?

Blizzard will share your personal information with third parties only in the ways that are described in this Privacy Policy.

We may, however, share non-personally identifiable, aggregated, and/or public information with third parties. Additionally, we share unique identifiers specific to your device with third parties to tailor content and to adjust and improve our services.

We may share your personal information with our affiliated companies for the purposes described in this Privacy Policy. If you purchase a product or license a game from another company on our Battle.net platform, we may share some of your account information with that company so they may establish a direct relationship with you. Because of that sharing, you may receive communications from that company.

We share some of our players’ game data with our community of developers who create applications and websites that benefit our player community. You may opt-out of having your game data included in this program by opting out of game-data sharing in the Privacy section of Battle.net account management.

We reserve the right to disclose your Information if we are required to do so by law. We may also disclose your information to law enforcement or in civil litigation in connection with the enforcement of our rights or your legal obligations (e.g., bringing legal action against you if you are violating the EULA).

We may share your information with vendors Blizzard engages to perform services for Blizzard (for example, platform providers, media partners, event ticket providers, merchandise vendors, survey providers, billing, consumer services support, information technology hardware and software). In these situations, a written contract between Blizzard and the vendor shall control such disclosure, the vendor must agree to reasonable levels of security regarding your data and the vendor will not be permitted to use your data except as required for the performance of those services for Blizzard. If your data is anonymized, the vendor may use it for other purposes.

As with any business, your personal information is also an asset of Blizzard and will become part of our normal business records. As such, we may also disclose your personal information to a third party if we decide to sell a line of business to that third party, so you can continue to receive service and information in connection with that line of business with as little disruption as possible. Similarly, in the event of a merger, acquisition, reorganization, bankruptcy, or other similar event, your personal information may be transferred to Blizzard's successor or assign.

Blizzard may also have message boards, forums, and/or chat areas, where users can exchange ideas and communicate with one another. When posting to a message board, forum, or chat area, the information is being made publicly available online and the user does so at his or her own risk. For certain forums, anyone posting or replying to a post may be doing so using their Real ID -- that is, their full first and last name -- with the option to also display the name of their primary in-game character (see discussion regarding Real ID below). If your personal information is posted on one of our community forums, you may contact us at [dataprivacy@blizzard.com](mailto:dataprivacy@blizzard.com) to request removal. Sometimes, we may not be able to remove your personal information, in which case we will let you know if we cannot do so and why.

## 5\. What choices do you have regarding the collection, use, and distribution of your personal information?

You have choices over the Information provided by you and by other sources, and how Blizzard uses that Information. You can exercise your choices by updating your preferences at any time and also by managing your settings in your Battle.net account, on your devices and third party accounts.

### Your Choices About Information Provided by You

If you do not want to provide Blizzard with personal information, then you can choose not to provide it. If you choose not to provide us with personal information, we may not always be able to provide you with the Blizzard product or service you want. For example, without providing an email address, you cannot create a Battle.net account.

### Your Choices About Information Provided by Third Parties

You may control how third parties collect and share your Information by changing your preferences or opting out of collection directly with those third parties. Before disclosing Information to third parties, we recommend you check their respective privacy policies for further details.

### Your Choices About Blizzard Using Your Information

You can exercise choices over how Blizzard uses your personal information and update your preferences at any time:

• to remove yourself from receiving targeted email marketing or newsletters from Blizzard, simply click the unsubscribe link in the email or access your Battle.net account and edit your email communication preferences. You will need your password to access your account;

• to disable selected Cookies from collecting information relating to the effectiveness of advertising campaigns or analytics data and from serving you with personalized advertising, please see our [Cookie Policy](https://www.blizzard.com/en-us/cookies); and

• To remove having your game-data available to our community of application developers, opt-out of game-data sharing in the Privacy section of Battle.net account management.

If you opt-out of receiving email marketing communications from us, please note we may still contact you occasionally about the status of your account, such as to inform you that your account may be expiring, or for other service related information.

## 6\. California Residents: Your California Privacy Rights

### California Consumer Protection Act

Without being discriminated against for exercising these rights, California law gives its residents the right to request that we disclose what personal information we collect from you, to delete that information, and to opt-out of the sale of your personal information (if we sell such information), subject to certain restrictions. For security purposes, we will verify your identity – in part by requesting certain information from you -- when you request to exercise your California privacy rights. You also have the right to designate an agent to exercise these rights on your behalf. This section describes how to exercise those rights and our process for handling those requests.

**Right to Know:**  
If you are a California resident, you may submit, free of charge, but no more than twice in a 12-month period, a verifiable request for the following information:

• The specific pieces of personal information we have about you;

• The categories of personal information we collected, sold, or disclosed for a business purpose about you within the last 12 months;

• The categories of sources from which the personal information was collected;

• The purposes for which the information was collected or sold; and

• The categories of third parties to whom the information was sold, disclosed for a business purpose, or otherwise shared.

If possible, we will provide this information to you in a readily usable format that allows transmission to another entity. The easiest way to submit a request and receive your report is to click here to access our online [webform](https://us.battle.net/support/en/help/product/services/1327); alternatively, you may fill out this [form](https://www.blizzard.com/en-us/legal/3039ecc8-387d-41a1-ab03-d3c5b0d77131/blizzard-right-to-know) and then mail your request to Blizzard Entertainment, One Blizzard Way, Irvine, CA 92618-3616, USA, Attention: Data Protection Team. If we need additional information to verify your identity, we will contact you to request that information, which may include personal information about you or information about your past purchases or use of Blizzard’s products or services. If we deny your request, even if only in part, we will explain the reason in our response.

**Right to Data Portability:**  
Data portability is the ability to move data from one company to another (for instance, when you transfer your mobile phone service to another carrier). While this right is not very applicable to Blizzard’s current business, we will provide you with an electronic file with your most basic account information, should you request it. The easiest way to submit a request for deletion is to click here to access our online [webform](https://us.battle.net/support/en/help/product/services/1327) ; you may fill out this [form](https://www.blizzard.com/en-us/legal/db319806-ae84-458e-8593-5161c0fde19c/blizzard-portability) and then mail your request to Blizzard Entertainment, One Blizzard Way, Irvine, CA 92618-3616, USA, Attention: Data Protection Team.

**Right to Delete:**  
If you are a California resident, you may submit a verifiable request for us to delete the personal information we have collected about you. **The deletion of a Battle.net account is permanent and cannot be reversed; also, all games, assets and history will also be permanently deleted.** We may retain personal information necessary to: (a) protect our business, systems, and users from fraudulent activity, (b) to address technical issues that impair existing functionality, (c) necessary for us, or others, to exercise their free speech or other rights, (d) comply with law enforcement requests pursuant to lawful process, (e) for scientific or historical research, (f) for our own internal purposes reasonably related to your relationship with us, or to comply with legal obligations. Additionally, we need certain types of information so we can provide our games and services to you. The easiest way to submit a request for deletion is to click here to access our online [webform](https://us.battle.net/support/en/help/product/services/1327); you may fill out this [form](https://www.blizzard.com/en-us/legal/14c3059f-905b-4b2c-9456-12a6e77dbc6c/blizzard-right-to-delete) and then mail your request to Blizzard Entertainment, One Blizzard Way, Irvine, CA 92618-3616, USA, Attention: Data Protection Team. If we need additional information to verify your identity, we will contact you to request that information. If we deny your request, even if only we will explain the reason in our response.

**Right to Opt-Out:**  
California residents may opt out of the “sale” of their personal information, as defined by the CCPA. This does not include when:

• You direct us to disclose your personal information or use us to interact with a third party and the third party does not sell the personal information;  
• We use or share an identifier solely to alert a third party you have opted out of the sale of your personal information;  
• Your personal information is transferred as an asset as part of a transaction in which the third party assumes control of all or part of our business, in which case the third party would have to tell you in writing if it materially changes how the information is used or shared; and  
• We use or share your personal information under a written contract with a service provider necessary to perform a business purpose. Here, the service the service provider performs is on our behalf, and our written contract prohibits it from keeping, using or disclosing your personal information for any purpose other than for the specific purpose identified in the contract.

In these cases, the disclosure of your personal information would not be considered a “sale” under CCPA. We use and share your information as described in this privacy policy and do not believe this use and sharing is a sale as defined by the CCPA. We have not sold personal information about you in the last 12 months and currently have no plans to do so in the future. However, we have provided you with a system to record your preference that your data not be sold in the future. You may make this request by clicking this [link](https://us.battle.net/support/en/help/product/services/1327) or by filling out this [form](https://www.blizzard.com/en-us/legal/965284ab-1cf2-4370-92db-880b83b8ee20/blizzard-right-to-opt-out) and mailing it to us at Blizzard Entertainment, One Blizzard Way, Irvine, CA 92618-3616, USA, Attention: Data Protection Team.

**Right to be Free from Discrimination:**  
We may not discriminate against you because you have exercised your rights, including, for example, by denying you access to our online services or charging you different rates or prices for the same online services, unless that difference is reasonably related to the value provided by your data.

**Authorized Agents:**  
If you would like to designate an authorized agent to make a request on your behalf, please be sure the agent can (i) demonstrate you have provided written permission for the agent to submit the request on your behalf, and (ii) provide proof of his or her own identity. If the agent does not satisfy these requirements, we will deny the request.

### California Shine the Light Law

Since 2005, California Civil Code Section 1798.83 permits our customers who are California residents to request certain information regarding our disclosure of personal information to third parties for their direct marketing purposes. We do not share our customer's personal information with unaffiliated third parties for their own direct marketing purposes. For inquiries regarding our disclosure policy, please send us an email to [dataprivacy@blizzard.com](mailto:dataprivacy@blizzard.com) , or write us at: Blizzard Entertainment, One Blizzard Way, Irvine, CA 92618-3616, USA, Attention: Data Protection Team. We will be happy to honor your request.

### Privacy Rights for California Minors in the Digital World

Since January 1, 2015, California Business and Professions Code Section 22581 permits California residents under the age of 18 to have the right to view, correct and request the removal of content or information they have posted to the message boards or forums. This request can be made by contacting us at Blizzard Entertainment, One Blizzard Way, Irvine, CA 92618-3616 Attention: Privacy Policy Administrator. We can also be reached via e-mail at [dataprivacy@blizzard.com](mailto:dataprivacy@blizzard.com). Note that any information posted to the message boards or forums is publicly viewable. We strongly recommend that all users avoid posting personal or sensitive information.

Residual copies of content and/or information that have been deleted may remain on our backup servers. We do not have to remove posted content or information if it has been rendered anonymous. We may retain your Information to resolve disputes, enforce our user agreements, or comply with legal requirements; in this case, your personal information will be blocked from use for any other purpose. Additionally, we do not have control over third parties (e.g., other users) who may have copied or reposted the content or information.

### Do Not Track

California Business and Professions Code Section 22575(b) (as amended effective January 1, 2014) permits our customers who are California residents to be informed as to how Blizzard responds to Web browser "Do Not Track" settings. As Do Not Track is a standard that is currently being developed, Blizzard does not take actions to respond to Do Not Track settings, and instead we adhere to the standards set out in this Privacy Policy. To find out more about Do Not Track you may find the following link useful: <http://www.allaboutdnt.com/> .

## 7\. Children and Parents

**Children Under 13**  
Once a child states that his/her age is under 13, they will be unable to register an account with us. We do not knowingly collect or store any personally identifiable information from children under 13. If parents believe that we have unintentionally collected their children’s’ personal information, they may request the deletion of the information by contacting us at Blizzard Entertainment Privacy Policy, Attention: Privacy Policy Administrator, One Blizzard Way, Irvine CA USA 92618-3616. They may also e-mail us at [dataprivacy@blizzard.com](mailto:dataprivacy@blizzard.com).

**Note to Parents**  
We recognize a special obligation to protect personal information about young children. We urge parents to instruct their children to never give out their real names, addresses, or phone numbers, without permission, when online. Teenagers under the age of 17 and over the age of 12 should encourage their parents to review this policy and to contact us if they would like to evoke our opt-out capabilities or to raise any concerns. For more information, you may visit our Parental Controls area at <https://us.battle.net/account/parental-controls/index.html>.

## 8\. What is Real ID?

Real ID friends can see each other’s real-life name and can see each other’s characters across all Blizzard products and services. By participating in Real ID, you will have the option of making your real name visible to your friend’s friends, who will also be able to invite you to become friends. The controls for Real ID are located in Battle.net account management.

When you and a friend mutually agree to become Real ID friends, you will have access to several additional features, including:

• Real Names for Friends: Your Real ID friends will appear under their real-life names on your friends list, when chatting, communicating in-game, or viewing a character's profile.

• Cross-Realm and Cross-Game Chat: With Real ID, friends can chat cross-realm, cross-faction, and cross-game using Blizzard’s products and services.

• Rich Presence: You will see additional info on your friends list about what your Real ID friends are up to in Blizzard’s products and services in real time.

## 9\. What is Global Play?

Certain Blizzard games feature "Global Play," which allows you to play with other players outside of the region associated with the creation of your Blizzard account. This feature is very beneficial to players who travel frequently or have friends and family in other regions. The Global Play feature requires that some or all of the personal information that you provided when you created your Blizzard account be transferred to servers operated by Blizzard in other regions.

## 10\. What are tracking technologies and how are they used?

As is true with most websites, we gather certain information automatically and store it in log files. This information may include a unique identifier such as your Internet Protocol (IP) address and non-personal information such as your browser type, Internet Service Provider (ISP), referring/exit pages, operating system, date/time stamp, and/or clickstream data. We may combine this automatically collected log information with other information we collect about you. We do this to improve the services we offer you, to improve marketing, analytics, or website functionality.

Blizzard and our partners, such as marketing partners and analytics providers ([listed here](https://www.blizzard.com/en-us/legal/7fac8c01-ac9c-4c51-82ec-1f535e1f54ba/marketing-partners)), may use tracking technologies such as cookies, beacons, tags and scripts. These technologies are used in analyzing trends, administering the websites, tracking users’ movements around the websites, and to gather demographic information about our user base. We may receive reports based on the use of these technologies by these companies on an individual and aggregated basis.

We use cookies for various purposes including our shopping cart, to remember users’ settings (e.g. language preference), and for authentication. Users can control the use of cookies at the individual browser level. If you reject cookies, you may still use our websites, but your ability to use features or areas of our websites may be limited.

We may also use clear gifs in our HTML-based emails to let us know which e-mails have been opened by recipients. This allows us to gauge the effectiveness of certain communications and the effectiveness of our marketing campaigns. These types of clear gifs are tied to personally identifiable information.

We, and third parties with whom we partner to provide certain features on our websites or to display advertising based on your web browsing activity, use Local Shared Objects such as Flash cookies, and Local Storage such as HTML5, to store content information and preferences. Various browsers may offer their own management tools for removing HTML5. To manage Flash cookies, lease [click here](http://www.macromedia.com/support/documentation/en/flashplayer/help/settings_manager07.html).

We partner with third party ad networks to manage our advertising on other sites. Our ad network partners may use tracking technologies to collect information about your activities on this and other websites to provide you targeted advertising based upon your interests. Some of these ad networks are members of the Networking Advertising Initiative (“NAI”) and/or the Digital Advertising Alliance (“DAA”) – organizations who offer a single location to opt out of receiving tailored ads. If you wish to not have your information used to serve you targeted ads, you may opt-out by visiting the [DAA’s Consumer Choice page](http://www.aboutads.info/choices/) and/or the [NAI’s Consumer Opt-Out page](http://www.networkadvertising.org/choices/). Please note this does not opt you out of being served advertising. You will continue to receive generic, or non-targeted, ads. Please also note that we strive to adhere to the [DAA’s Self-Regulatory Principles for Online Behavioral Advertising](http://digitaladvertisingalliance.org/sites/aboutads/files/DAA_files/seven-principles-07-01-09.pdf).

## 11\. What are Internet Protocol addresses?

An Internet Protocol ("IP") address is the unique number assigned to your server or Internet Service Provider ("ISP"). Blizzard may track such IP addresses for system administration, to report aggregate information, site tracking, security purposes, or to prevent our servers from being abused. See the tracking technology discussion above.

## 12\. What do you do to obtain a report about the personal information Blizzard holds about you or delete your personal information?

You may submit, free of charge, but no more than twice in a 12-month period, a verifiable request for the personal information we have about you. To obtain the report, click here to access our online [webform](https://us.battle.net/support/en/help/product/services/1327).

You may also submit a verifiable request for us to delete either: (1) your marketing information; or (2) your Battle.net account and your marketing information. **The deletion of a Battle.net account is permanent and cannot be reversed; also, all games, assets and history will also be permanently deleted.** We may retain personal information to: (a) protect our business, systems, and users from fraudulent activity, (b) to address technical issues that impair existing functionality, (c) necessary for us, or others, to exercise their free speech or other rights, (d) comply with law enforcement requests pursuant to lawful process, (e) for scientific or historical research, (f) for our own internal purposes reasonably related to your relationship with us, or to comply with legal obligations. To submit a request for deletion, click here to access our online [webform](https://us.battle.net/support/en/help/product/services/1327).

Note: California residents may have additional rights; please see Section 6.

## 13\. How secure is your personal information?

Blizzard takes a range of security measures designed to protect your personal information and keep it confidential (unless it is non-confidential by nature, for example, publicly-available information like user generated content, leaderboard rankings, forum posts and scores, etc.). We also take steps to ensure that the personal information collected is protected from misuse and alteration. In addition, we request vendors who process personal information on our behalf to themselves take a range of security measures designed to help protect your personal information. However, the Internet by its nature is not a secure environment and the nature of security risks is constantly evolving, as are the technical and organizational industry standards relating to management of those risks. The complete security of any personal information collected, stored or used by us or our vendors cannot therefore be guaranteed.

It is very important for you to understand that you control the security of your account to a great extent. Choosing a password you don’t use on any other system is important. Changing that password occasionally is also a good idea. Another way to substantially increase your account security is to add a free Blizzard authenticator app to your phone; just go to the app store for your phone and download it at no cost to you.

## 14\. Help for People with Disabilities:

If you have a disability that makes exercising any of your rights in this Privacy Policy difficult, we want to help you through alternative means. Please contact us, and let us know how we may best help you, at [DataPrivacy@blizzard.com](mailto:dataprivacy@blizzard.com) or 877-566-3886 or Blizzard Entertainment, One Blizzard Way, Irvine, CA 92618-3616, USA, Attention: Data Protection Team.

## 15\. What if you have a question or complaint?

If you have questions or wish to file a complaint, please e-mail us at [DPO@blizzard.com](mailto:DPO@blizzard.com) or send a letter addressed to Blizzard Entertainment, One Blizzard Way, Irvine, CA 92618-3616, Attention: Data Protection Officer.

As mentioned, Blizzard Entertainment is a licensee of ESRB’s Privacy Certified Program. If you believe that we have not responded to your inquiry or your inquiry has not been satisfactorily addressed, please contact ESRB Privacy Certified at <http://www.esrb.org/privacy/contact.aspx>, or ESRB, Attention: Vice President, Privacy Certified Program, 420 Lexington Ave., Suite 2024, New York, NY 10170. You may also e-mail them at [privacy@esrb.org](mailto:privacy@esrb.org).

This Privacy Policy was last updated on December 20, 2019
